<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SUSTech BIO210 Biostatistics</title>
    <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SUSTech BIO210 Biostatistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:10 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4 Probability Axioms</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:10 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-04/</guid>
      <description>Probability Axioms After we finished the content of descriptive statistics, we moved on to the section of probability, which is really good at dealing with randomness. You have probably already come across some concepts of probability. In Lecture 4, we just made things formal. Probability axioms were introduced in this lecture. Those are the things we need to agree on. They are quite intuitive, and hopefully, you have no problem accepting them as facts:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3 Numerical Measures</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-03/</guid>
      <description>Numerical Measures Lecture 3 concludes the section of descriptive statistics. From the previous lectures we demonstrated that graphs were a nice way of showing the data. One can immediately get a rough idea about how the data look like from a good graph. However, when the data is presented in graphs, the quantitative information in the data is lost. Therefore, it would be good if we could just use a bunch of numbers to summarise the data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2 Descriptive Statistics</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:10 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-02/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 2 started to introduce some basic techniques in descriptive statistics. You can think of this lecture as a recap of what you have already known in the past. Make sure you get familiar with all the graphs introduced in this lecture, because we are going to use them all the time in future lectures. Perhaps the most important graph in this course is the histogram, which is the most common way of showing frequency distributions:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1 Course Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-01/</guid>
      <description>In the first lecture of the entire course, we had a brief overview of the course structure and content. Lecture 1 started with some administrative aspects of the course. Then we provided an introduction about what is and is NOT included in the course, what to expect from the course and the difference between BIO210 and MA212.&#xA;Your final grade is a weighted average 1 of the following:&#xA;Attendance Homework Mid-term Final exam $10\%$ $20\%$ $30\%$ $40\%$ Not much stuff in this lecture really, so you could just relax and listen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List of all course content</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 16:01:31 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/course/</guid>
      <description>All course content Lesson 1 (23-Feb-2024) Lecture slides Lecture 1 Introduction To BIO210 Lecture 2 Data Presentation Homework assignment None Extra reading material None Lesson 2 (28-Feb-2024) Lecture slides Lecture 3 Numerical Measures Lecture 4 Probability Axioms Homework assignment Assignment 1 Extra reading material None </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome To BIO210 Biostatistics</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 16:01:31 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/about/</guid>
      <description>This static website holds all course material from the BIO210 Biostatistics course delivered by the School of Life Sciences at SUSTech, Shenzhen. This is an entry level statistics course for undergraduates who have no prior knowledge about statistics at all. We do assume you are familiar with the math from your high school and the 1st year undergraduate training.&#xA;About This Website You can find all material listed in this Content Index page, typically a few days before or after the actual lesson.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
