<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on SUSTech BIO210 Biostatistics</title>
    <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on SUSTech BIO210 Biostatistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 10 Random Variables</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-10/</guid>
      <description>In this lecture, we are introducing perhaps the first &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo;1 concept in this course: random variables. It is very important to understand the concepts of random variables and the expectation and variance of a random variable. When coming across something new, always start with something simple to get a rough idea. Therefore, we use some simple and intuitive examples, such as coin tossing, during the lectures.
Random Variables A random variable is defined as a a real-valued function defined on a sample space $\Omega$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 9 Counting</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-09/</guid>
      <description>In Lecture 9, we are going to pause a little bit and do a quick recap about the basic counting principles. The content is basically what you have learnt during your high school math classes but in English. You will see that the counting principles we are talking about greatly help us calculate the probability of events consisting outcomes from discrete sample spaces.
You might ask why we bother to do a recap about counting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 8 Independent Events</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-08/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 8 introduces the concept of independence. It is a relatively straightforward concept to understand. Intuitively, events $A$ and $B$ are independent if:
$$\mathbb{P}(A|B)=\mathbb{P}(A), \mathbb{P}(B) \neq 0$$
Using Bayes&amp;rsquo; terms, we can say that the posterior probability is equal to the prior probability. In other words, event $B$ has nothing to do with $A$; event $B$ does not provide any information about event $A$; given that event $B$ has occurred, we do not change our belief about event $A$ &amp;hellip; Recall that from Lecture 5, we have:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 7 More On The Bayes Theorem</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-07/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 7 introduces more examples of using the Bayes&amp;rsquo; theorem to help us make decisions in real life. Sometimes, the conclusion seems counterintuitive at the beginning. However, if you grasp the idea of using the new information to update your prior belief, you will find the Bayes&amp;rsquo;s rule very natural. We will also introduce a new form of the Bayes&amp;rsquo; rule without talking about the events $A$, $B$ etc.:
$$\mathbb{P}(H_i|E) = \cfrac{\mathbb{P}(H_i)\mathbb{P}(E|H_i)}{\mathbb{P}(E)} = \cfrac{\mathbb{P}(E|H_i)}{\sum_{i=1}^n \mathbb{P}(H_i)\mathbb{P}(E|H_i)} \cdot \mathbb{P}(H_i)$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 6 The Bayes&#39; Theorem</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-06/</guid>
      <description>Now we have get familiar with conditional probabilities. The basic definition and formula is:
$$\mathbb{P}(A|B)=\cfrac{\mathbb{P}(A \cap B)}{\mathbb{P}(B)} \textmd{, } \mathbb{P}(B) \neq 0$$
In the previous lecture, we used some examples to show how to calculate three probabilities: $\mathbb{P}(A \cap B)$, $\mathbb{P}(B)$ and $\mathbb{P}(A|B)$, which are essentially the three terms in the above formula. In reality, we sometimes need to calculate some very complicated probabilities, but they all boils down to some sort of combinations of those three probabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 5 Conditional Probability</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-05/</guid>
      <description>In Lectures 5, we will introduce the concept of conditional probability and see how we could use it to learn from the real world. Whenever we come across a new concept, the first thing is always to build up our intuition about it. Using a few simple examples, we start to get some ideas about conditional probabilities.
In conditional probability, we are interested in calculating the probability of an event when taking into account some knowledge that we have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4 Probability Axioms</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-04/</guid>
      <description>Probability Axioms After we finished the content of descriptive statistics, we will move on to the section of probability, which is really good at dealing with randomness. You have probably already come across some concepts of probability. In Lecture 4, we will make things formal. Probability axioms will be introduced. Those are the things we need to agree on. They are quite intuitive, and hopefully, you will have no problem accepting them as facts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3 Numerical Measures</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-03/</guid>
      <description>Numerical Measures Lecture 3 concludes the section of descriptive statistics. From the previous lectures we demonstrated that graphs were a nice way of showing the data. One can immediately get a rough idea about how the data look like from a good graph. However, when the data is presented in graphs, the quantitative information in the data is lost. Therefore, it would be good if we could just use a bunch of numbers to summarise the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2 Descriptive Statistics</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-02/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 2 starts to introduce some basic techniques in descriptive statistics. You can think of this lecture as a recap of what you have already known in the past. Make sure you get familiar with all the graphs introduced in this lecture, because we are going to use them all the time in future lectures. Perhaps the most important graph in this course is the histogram, which is the most common way of showing frequency distributions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1 Course Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dbrg77.github.io/SUSTech-BIO210/posts/lecture-01/</guid>
      <description>In the first lecture of the entire course, we will have a brief overview of the course structure and content. Lecture 1 starts with some administrative aspects of the course. Then we will provide an introduction about what is and is not included in the course, what to expect from the course and the difference between BIO210 and MA212.
Your final grade is a weighted average 1 of the following:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
